

Joshua Shone

Full-stack developer

Sept. 26, 1989
(S) josh.shone

@ josh.shone@gmail.com

\(+49 1765 793 7870

Berlin

Hi, I'm Josh - a full-stack web and native applications developer living in Berlin (originally from Canberra, Australia). I have 7 years experience, covering UX/UI design, native applications, low-level multimedia processing and modern HTML5/JS using Agile methodologies and continuous integration.

Employment

KIWI.KI GmbH

Full-stack web developer

Developed and released an overhauled version of KIWI's web app for housing companies, covering backend work in Python/

Flask and frontend work in node.js/backbone. Also implemented user experience improvements to KIWI's consumer web frontend.

General Dynamics Mediaware

2012 - 2015 3 years, 4 months

2016 - present

6 months

Berlin

■ Native application programmer ■ Web developer

Canberra, Australia

Initial role as C++ programmer engaged in performance analysis, debugging and feature development on a large codebase. Worked in a mid-sized Agile team adhering to well-defined processes for issue-tracking, continuous integration, customer feedback and development iterations.

Helped develop the company's flagship product InStream, a high-performance multi-threaded video processing service for broadcast television. Also engaged in R&D, producing working prototypes for new products - one of which went on to be used by Australian firefighting services.

Took on a new role as primary web developer after showing initiative by producing performance analysis tooling with HTML5. Went on to develop a company-wide framework for service control utilizing cutting-edge web standards including websocket-based RPC (WAMP) and reactor-based networking (Twisted). Was also responsible for UI design, mockups, user-testing and producing high-quality documentation.

NCH Software

2009 - 2012

■ UI Designer ■ Native application developer

3 years, 4 months



Was responsible for creating several native desktop applications from scratch, including a non-destructive photo editor and musical notation software. Initial concept, design, mockups, prototyping, development and release was handled either solo or in small teams. Highlights:

- Designed a unique modeless editing UI for sheet music.
- Implemented a dynamic level-of-detail system for smoothly scaling fast fourier transform visualizations.
- Developed a high-performance non-destructive image transformation and layering system.

Education

Academy of Interactive Entertainment

ন্ত্ৰ Adv. Diploma of Professional Game Development

P Canberra, Australia

2007 - 2008

© Cert IV in 3D Animation for Games and Film

Covered a broad range of computer science and visual design topics, including:

- · Composition, layout and prototyping
- · Realtime games programming in C++ (Visual Studio)
- 3D content creation and animation (3dsMax)
- Use of realtime graphics engines (Unreal)

Skills

HTML5/CSS3

4 years professional experience with modern web standards, client-side rendering, responsive design etc.

Node.JS

Have used node for its build tooling/package ecosystem in production.

SASS

Have atomic-design structured SASS in production, with high browser compatibility.

Python

Gained a deep knowledge after using Python professionally for many years in server-side networking. It's my go-to choice for any trivial math/logic problem, but I have experience using it at scale too.

Polymer

Currently giving Polymer 1.2 a good workout in a personal project, and would be stoked to use it at work.

C++

Long and deeply involved history with C++ at work, in personal projects and while studying games programming. Strong OOP design, multi-threaded/high-performance disciplines, advanced use of language features.

Bower

Good working knowledge of bower dependency management.

socket.io

Up to speed with socket.io 1.0 rooms, namespaces, binary encodings etc. Also have a deeper knowledge of the underlying mechanisms, i.e. websockets, long-polling.

KnockoutJS

Extensive in-depth use, pushing the library to its performance limits and extending its capabilities.

Twisted

3+ years experience working with Twisted, including interfacing with C++ codebases using non-blocking RPC (WAMP) and other advanced usages.

Javascript

Experience with developing large, well structured JS codebases, with a growing knowledge of ES6/ES7 language features.

Backbone.js

Have developed and deployed backbone applications to production.

SQL

Experience writing SQL-backed apps - async/non-blocking and high-performance.

Git

Used extensively both professionally and personally. Have a solid understanding of underlying concepts.

jQuery

Used liberally in past work projects.

Bootstrap

Used fairly comprehensively in the past.

Coffeescript

Used pretty rigorously in a past personal project; would be delighted to use it again.

Gulp

Up to speed with writing and managing gulp tasks for optimization, deployment etc.

Go

Covered briefly in a previous personal project. Certainly an enthusiast of Go and keen to put it to good use again.

Linux

Many years experience both personally and professionally. My ideal development environment is in Linux.